MATT JONES

m.r.jones@live.co.uk \primattjones.wales \primattle LinkedIn

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack software engineer with 6 years of experience working in agile teams. Technical experience includes extensive work with React and building RESTFul microservices. A strong believer in XP practices with an emphasis on collaboration, feedback, and user-focused development. Experience with mentoring junior developers.

SKILLS

Frontend Typescript, React, NextJS, Cypress, Jest, Svelte/SvelteKit, Tailwindcss, Less, Webpack, Vite Backend Kotlin, Spring Boot, Java, JUnit, Keycloak, Node.js, Python

Developer Tools Git, ConcourseCI, Kubernetes, GCP, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, Docker, Grafana,

Prometheus, Terraform

EXPERIENCE

Boclips, Full Stack Engineer, London, UK/Remote

Nov 2018 - Dec 2023 \cdot 4 years 2 months

Working for a London ed-tech startup in an XP team, providing a media streaming platform through various integrations. Spent the last 3 months as a tech lead

Kotlin, TypeScript, React, Kubernetes, GCP, Elasticsearch, DDD, TDD, XP

- Built and maintained full-stack applications. React & Typescript webapps, backed by Spring Boot microservices implemented in Kotlin, all orchestrated by Kubernetes on GCP.
- Collaborated with the PM, UX designers, and engineering leads to shape delivery and implementation plans.
- Managed technical debt to ensure it was addressed in a sustainable manner.
- Modernized tech stack, whilst migrating code and customers away from a legacy system.
- Improved web application load times using various techniques, such as caching and code splitting.
- Managed and mentored a junior engineer.
- Conducted initial technical interviews to hire engineers across all levels.
- Organised weekly "Lunch and Learn" sessions for the engineering team to promote knowledge sharing.
- Facilitated (including company-wide) retrospectives to evaluate and improve team processes.
- Practiced pair programming, TDD, and all other XP fun.

Hawk-Eye Innovations, Software Engineer, Remote

Oct 2017 - Jun 2018 \cdot 9 months

Working in Hawk-Eye's SMARTData team, developed data-driven web technologies and real-time broadcasting graphics engines in an agile environment.

Java, Spring Boot, HTML5, React, TypeScript

- Optimised an HTML5 data-driven broadcast graphics engine for FIVB's Volleyball Nations League
- Enhanced an interactive timeline for use alongside Hawk-Eye's core replay software
- Played a significant role in sprint planning, backlog prioritization, and pull request reviews

Hawk-Eye Innovations, Junior Software Engineer (Placement), Basingstoke

Jun 2015 - Aug 2016 \cdot 1 year 3 months

I was a junior software developer working in Hawk-Eye's replay technology team, working on projects related to some of the world's top sporting events. Responsibilities included delivering new features and general bug fixing.

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) in Computer Science with Placement Year, Bath University

2013-2017